<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<addon id="script.advanced.wowan"
       name="Advanced Wake on WAN"
       version="0.1"
       provider-name="-Sio-">
  <requires>
        <import addon="xbmc.python" version="2.7.0"/>
  </requires>
  <extension point="xbmc.python.script"
             library="default.py" />
  <extension point="xbmc.service"
             library="autostart.py" />
  <extension point="xbmc.addon.metadata">
	<platform>all</platform>
    <summary lang="en">Addon to wake remote server using only a URL:Port (WoWAN) if supported by router</summary>
    <description lang="en">Wake a remote server by accessing it through the web.
	Needs a router settings like "Start this computer automatically as soon as it is accessed from the internet" and a port forwarded from the router to this machine as well as a static IP or some kind of dnyDNS.
	The chosen port can be anything and the server doesn't even have to respond to it. The fact that something tries to contact the server from the internet is sufficient for the router to send a local WoL signal to the server.
	The URL must be like these examples: http://www.yourdyndns.com or https://www.yourdyndns.com:63214 or ftp://123.123.123.123:32049
	For availability checks, there is an option to ping the LAN Address (in a VPN for example) of the remote device you tried to wake up.
------------------------
The Addon can be launched manually from the Programs-section of Kodi (and thus added to your favorites, etc.), and can also be configured in the addon-settings to autostart with Kodi (advised if the remote server also has the MySQL), thus waking up your remote device when Kodi starts.
There is also a setting that will also send a wake-up signal, if Kodi comes out from standby/sleep/suspend.
------------------------
When autostarted with Kodi you can also set the addon to update the video- and/or music-libraries automatically after a successful wake-up.
You can also set up a delay for the library scans. This is needed, if the file system needs some further time to get ready after a successful wake-up.
------------------------
In the advanced settings you can also set the addon to continue sending WoWAN packets with a configurable delay.
This is useful, when the remote device or NAS is kept awake, as long as WoWAN-packets are received or gets woken up again if it went to sleep.
Normally the continuous WoWAN-packets will also continue after Kodi has returned from standby/sleep/suspend, but there is an option to turn this behavior off.
------------------------
If for any reason the check of a successful wake-up via ping is not possible or fails on your system, please note the following:
  - Kodi must be run as Administrator on Windows / with root rights on Linux for ping-based host-up checks to work.
  - If this is not possible or it still fails, you can disable ping-based host-up checks in the advanced addon-settings.
    This allows you to set a fixed timespan, after which the addon just assumes, that the remote host is awake (to display success-notifies, launch other commands, etc.).</description>
    <disclaimer lang="en">This addon is a core modified version of the &quot;Advanced Wake On Lan&quot; version 1.2.5 by mandark which uses the GNU GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE. While keeping the general layout, structure and pretty much most of the framework the core WoL is replaced by a special version of WoL and WoWAN combined. It also uses the GPL-compatible and Open Source Python &quot;urllib2&quot;, &quot;Request&quot;, &quot;urlopen&quot;, &quot;URLError&quot;, to send the wakeup-packet and the GNU-licensed &quot;python-ping&quot;-script to determine the status of the server. Please see the file &quot;ping.py&quot; for infos on the latter one. Icons made by Kiranshastry from www.flaticon.com.</disclaimer>
    <license>GNU General Public License, v2</license>
	<forum>https://forum.kodi.tv/showthread.php?tid=350134</forum>
	<source>https://github.com/SioFFBE/kodi-script.advanced.wowan</source>
	<assets>
			<icon>icon.png</icon>
			<fanart>fanart.jpg</fanart>
			<screenshot>resources/screenshot1.png</screenshot>
			<screenshot>resources/screenshot2.png</screenshot>
			<screenshot>resources/screenshot3.png</screenshot>
		</assets>
  </extension>
</addon>
